washburn.edu 2004-12-08

# Web Privacy Statement, Washburn University

### Washburn University Web Privacy Statement

It is the practice of Washburn University to respect the privacy of all Web site visitors to the extent permitted by law. This Web privacy statement is intended to inform you of the ways in which this Web site collects information, how the information is used and what we do to protect any information you choose to provide us. 

There are four types of information that may be collected during your visit: network traffic information, Web server statistic logs, cookies, and information voluntarily provided by you. 

Network Traffic 

In the course of ensuring network security and consistent service for all users, the University may use software programs to do such things as:

  * Analyze network traffic 
  * Identify unauthorized access
  * Detect computer viruses and other software that might damage University computers or the network 
  * Monitor and maintain the performance of the University network

In the course of such monitoring, these programs may detect such information as e-mail headers, addresses from network packets and other information. Information from these activities is used solely for the purpose of maintaining the security and performance of the University's networks and computer systems. Personally identifiable information from these activities is not released to external parties unless required by law.

**Web Server Logs**

The University Web server collects and stores information from Web site visitors to monitor Web site performance and to improve service. This information includes the following: 

  * Page visited
  * Date and time of the visit
  * Domain name or IP address of the referring site
  * Domain name and IP address from which the access occurred
  * Version of browser used and the capabilities of the browser 
  * Search terms entered into our search engine

The University makes no attempt to identify individual visitors from this information: any personally identifiable information is not released to external parties unless required by law. 

**Cookies  
**  
Cookies are small bits of data stored on your hard drive on behalf of a Web site and returned to the Web site on request. This site may use cookies for two purposes: to carry data about your current session at the site from one Web page to the next, and to identify you to the site between visits. If you prefer not to receive cookies, you may turn them off in your browser, or may set your browser to ask you before accepting a new cookie. Some pages may not function properly if the cookies are turned off. Unless otherwise notified on this site, we will not store data, other than for these two purposes, in cookies. Cookies remain on your computer. We do not forward them to any external parties. Unless otherwise notified on this site, we do not use cookies to track your movement among different Web sites and do not exchange cookies with other entities. 

**Information Voluntarily Provided by You**

In the course of using this Web site, you may choose to provide us with information to help us serve your needs. For example, you may send us electronic mail (through a Web form or mailto: link) to request information, send an electronic postcard, register for events, or you may send us your address so we may send you an application or other materials. Any personally identifiable information you send us will be used only for the purpose indicated. Requests for information will be directed to the appropriate staff to respond to the request, and may be recorded to help us update our site to better respond to similar requests. We will not sell, exchange or otherwise distribute your personally identifiable information without your consent, except to the extent required by law. We do not retain the information longer than necessary for normal operations. Each Web page requesting information discloses the purpose of that information. Please contact the person listed on the specific page, or contact webmaster@washburn.edu with questions or concerns on the use of personally identifiable information.

**External Links**

University Web sites provide links to other World Wide Web sites or resources. We do not control these sites and resources, do not endorse them, and are not responsible for their availability, content, or delivery of services. In particular, external sites are not bound by the University's Web privacy policy; they may have their own policies or none at all. You can tell if you are leaving a University Web site by noting the URL of the destination site. 

If you have questions about this site, its collection of information, and its Web privacy statement, contact the University Webmaster at [webmaster@washburn.edu](mailto:webmaster@washburn.edu).

Last updated: 3/22/04
